<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://tianhom0919.github.io/tianhom/blog</id>
    <title>Welcome to my site! Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tianhom0919.github.io/tianhom/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Welcome to my site! Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://tianhom0919.github.io/tianhom/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[About LLMs]]></title>
        <id>https://tianhom0919.github.io/tianhom/blog/2025/9/11/blog-2</id>
        <link href="https://tianhom0919.github.io/tianhom/blog/2025/9/11/blog-2"/>
        <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[About LLMs]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Large language models such as ChatGPT have proven to be very useful in software development, especially during debugging.</p>
<p>ChatGPT has been a lifesaver for software engineers, as they can:</p>
<ul>
<li>paste error messages to ask where the error might be</li>
<li>ask to clarify how a code snippet works</li>
<li>ask for explanations about fundamental concepts</li>
<li>ask for code configuration</li>
</ul>
<h1>The Problem</h1>
<p>The biggest problem with LLMs is perhaps <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hallucination_(artificial_intelligence)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">hallucination</a>. Sometimes the answers generated may look very convincing, even though they are completely wrong. When programming, hallucinated code can often be caught quickly if it does not work. Problematic situations arise when the code seems to work, but contains bugs or security vulnerabilities that are harder to detect.</p>
<p>Another problem is that LLMs struggle to "understand" larger projects. Usually in a large project, making changes in one file would require changes to several other files. Because of token limits in ChatGPT, older parts of the conversation or input will be forgotten. This means that the language model is unable to generalize code, i.e. making small adjustments to reuse existing functions or components. This would result in the deterioration of the code base and decrease maintainability, as it generates a lot of repetitive code.</p>
<p>In this case, the responsibility lies with the programmer that uses language models. Quoting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Kernighan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brian Kerningham</a>, the co-author of <strong>The C Programming Language</strong>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>“Everyone knows that debugging is twice as hard as writing a program in the first place. So if you're as clever as you can be when you write it, how will you ever debug it?”</em></p>
<p><strong>Brian Kernighan</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Simply put, it is not worth programming code you don't understand, since debugging will be twice as hard as programming. How can debugging be even possible when the programming is outsourced to an LLM, where the developer does not understand the debugged code at all?</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Eng Tian Hom</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/tianhom0919</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Blog]]></title>
        <id>https://tianhom0919.github.io/tianhom/blog/2024/12/06/blog-1</id>
        <link href="https://tianhom0919.github.io/tianhom/blog/2024/12/06/blog-1"/>
        <updated>2024-12-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My first blog]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are a few tips you might find useful.</p>
<p>Simply add Markdown files (or folders) to the <code>blog</code> directory.</p>
<p>The blog post date can be extracted from filenames, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>2019-05-30-welcome.md</code></li>
<li><code>2019-05-30-welcome/index.md</code></li>
</ul>
<p>And if you don't want a blog: just delete this directory, and use <code>blog: false</code> in your Docusaurus config.</p>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>?</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><p>Nothing To See Here</p><p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="sip" src="https://tianhom0919.github.io/tianhom/assets/images/image-531fc18edac7ba494baec4f618d9ecfd.png" width="162" height="148" class="img_ev3q"></p></div></div></details>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Eng Tian Hom</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/tianhom0919</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>